// !-- questions and answers section--//
const questions = [
  {
    question:
      "The songs 'Red Skies' and 'Saved by Zero' were huge hits for which 80's band?",
    options: ["Flock of Seagulls", "The Fixx", "Duran Duran", "Depeche Mode"],
    answer: "The Fixx",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/pIe-Cj071l0?t=2",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Always the artistic innovator. Whose alter-ego was known as 'Ziggy Stardust'?",
    options: ["Iggy Pop", "Alice Cooper", "Lou Reed", "David Bowie"],
    answer: "David Bowie",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/D8R_u3Yfwcs?t=15",
  },

  {
    question:
      "One of the all-time greats. Who was the original guitarists for Led Zeppellin?",
    options: ["Peter Frampton", "Jeff Beck", "Larry Carlton", "Jimmy Page"],
    answer: "Jimmy Page",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/6d_wxEz1Cbg?t=19",
  },

  {
    question:
      'His music will live on forever. Who wrote the song "I Shot the Sheriff"?',
    options: ["Eric Clapton", "Leon Russell", "Bob Marley", "Bob Dylan"],
    answer: "Bob Marley",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/zGO8HN1QQdI?t=8",
  },

  {
    question:
      "'Should I Stay or Should I Go' was a huge hit for which British band?",
    options: [
      "The Ramones",
      "Velvet Underground",
      "The Sex Pistols",
      "The Clash",
    ],
    answer: "The Clash",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/e7tWqyM3r-g?t=29",
  },

  {
    question:
      '"Sweetest Tabboo" and "Smooth Operator" were huge hits for which singer?',
    options: ["Tina Marie", "Whitney Houston", "Sade", "Anita Baker"],
    answer: "Sade",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/kcPc18SG6uA?t=9",
  },

  {
    question:
      'At the age of 17 he played with Dizzy Gilespie. Who wrote the jazz standard "So What"?',
    options: [
      "John Coltrane",
      "Wes Montgomery",
      "Thelonius Monk",
      "Miles Davis",
    ],
    answer: "Miles Davis",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/mwHwlgBFVmM?t=10",
  },

  {
    question:
      'Hits like "Quimbare" among many. Who was crowned the "Queen of Salsa"?',
    options: ["Celia Cruz", "Olga Guillot", "Lola Flores", "La Lupe"],
    answer: "Celia Cruz",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/TxRWQHCSmUg?t=25",
  },

  {
    question:
      'Which band wrote and performed the hit theme song for the show "Bad Boys"?',
    options: ["UB40", "Inner Circle", "Third World", "Aswad"],
    answer: "Inner Circle",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/2Q3dGZPguSM?t=11",
  },

  {
    question:
      '"Birdland" was a huge hit for this jazz Giant in 1971 and has been covered by many others.',
    options: [
      "Charlie Parker",
      "Glen Miller",
      "Tower of Power",
      "Weather Report",
    ],
    answer: "Weather Report",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/vz7nMBLUnDc?t=12",
  },

  {
    question:
      "'Jailbreak' was a huge hit in the 70's. Who was the original front man for the band Thin Lizzy?",
    options: ["Sting", "Phil Lynott", "Steve Perry", "Rick Emmett"],
    answer: "Phil Lynott",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/dMko8DlY9IA?list=RDdMko8DlY9IA&t=9",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which singer was known as'Ol' Blue Eyes' and 'The Chairman of the Board'?",
    options: [
      "Frank Sinatra",
      "David Coverdale",
      "Andy Williams",
      "Perry Como",
    ],
    answer: "Frank Sinatra",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/ZEcqHA7dbwM?t=6",
  },

  {
    question:
      "'Moonglow' and 'Let's Dance' were big hits in the 1930's for this band leader?",
    options: ["Artie Shaw", "Tommy Dorsey", "Dave Brubeck", "Benny Goodman"],
    answer: "Benny Goodman",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/4dm3Ml9g_cs?t=3",
  },

  {
    question:
      'The song "Breezin" was a huge hit for this great guitarist and vocalist.',
    options: [
      "Eddie Van Halen",
      "Mateo Mancusso",
      "Carlos Santana",
      "George Benson",
    ],
    answer: "George Benson",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/zgxL-khJ--Q?t=7",
  },

  {
    question:
      "A huge part of the British Invasion. What year did the Beatles play on Ed Sullivan?",
    options: ["1960", "1970", "1964", "1972"],
    answer: "1964",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/45cYwDMibGo?t=5",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Possibly know better for his solo career. Who was the original singer for Genesis?",
    options: ["David Vedder", "Phil Collins", "Billy Squire", "Peter Gabriel"],
    answer: "Peter Gabriel",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/OJWJE0x7T4Q?t=3",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Maybe the greatest rock guitar solo ever. Who was the guitarist on 'Eruption'?",
    options: ["Jimi Hendrix", "Steve Vai", "Joe Satriani", "Eddie Van Halen"],
    answer: "Eddie Van Halen",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/M4Czx8EWXb0?t=22",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The song,'Bamboleo' went mainstream for this Rumba Flamenca band?",
    options: [
      "Los Del Rio",
      "Gypsy Kings",
      "Gente De Zona",
      "Habana de Primera",
    ],
    answer: "Gypsy Kings",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/cqZg_w4_Y9Y?t=21",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Arguably the best Flamenco guitarist ever he wrote and played the song 'Entre Dos Aguas'.",
    options: ["Diego del Morao", "Tomatito", "Paco De Lucia", "Sabicas"],
    answer: "Paco De Lucia",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/2oyhlad64-s?t=4",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Lynard Skynard had many hits during his career, but this was not one of them.",
    options: [
      "Sweet Home Alabama",
      "Mississippi Queen",
      "Tuesday's Gone",
      "Mr. Saturday Night",
    ],
    answer: "Mississippi Queen",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/VbP4qf8PjfI?t=4",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The orangutan in the Jungle Book sings 'I wanna be like you'. Who is the voice behind the primate?",
    options: ["Dean Martin", "Bing Crosby", "Louie Prima", "Bobby Darin"],
    answer: "Louie Prima",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/u3oTAlHkpjU?t=105",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In what year was the Pink Floyd album 'Dark Side of the Moon' released?",
    options: ["1973", "1969", "1978", "1982"],
    answer: "1973",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/n3_5SPQIfQw",
  },

  {
    question:
      "This duo had numerous hits. A true musical icon. Who was Garfunkel's singing partner?",
    options: ["Garfinkle ", "Patsy Cline", "Simon", "Garfield"],
    answer: "Simon",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/JVdlpZ4M-Hw?t=2",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Geddy Lee was the original bassist and lead singer of which famous rock band?",
    options: ["King Crimson", "Rush", "Triumph", "Boston"],
    answer: "Rush",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/g_QtO0Rhp0w?t=7",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In this famous song by Eddie Money, how many tickets does he have to Paradise?",
    options: ["1", "8", "2", "3"],
    answer: "2",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/JxcUmAVG3RQ?t=3",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who is Jane 'through with' in this 1988 hit about drug abuse by Jane's Addiction?",
    options: ["Romeo", "Everybody", "Sergio", "Cameo"],
    answer: "Sergio",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/i7Q_8q3XXrQ?t=41",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In 1974, Led Zeppelin decided to launch their own record label. What was its name?",
    options: ["Led Balloon", "Cosmic", "Satellite", "Swan Song"],
    answer: "Swan Song",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/DBzuYNK95sM?t=3",
  },

  {
    question:
      "This all female rock band had a big hit with the song 'What's Up'. What is the name of this band?",
    options: ["The Go-Go's", "The Vandals", "the Bangles", "4 Non Blondes"],
    answer: "4 Non Blondes",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/6NXnxTNIWkc?t=3",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which American rock  band released 'Hard to Handle' along with 'Remedy' in 1990?",
    options: [
      "Nirvana",
      "Rage Against the Machine",
      "Black Crowes",
      "Molly Hatchet",
    ],
    answer: "Black Crowes",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/W1tEu_ByGos?t=4",
  },

  {
    question:
      "One of the great rock voices from the early 90's. Who is the lead singer for Pearl Jam?",
    options: ["Perry Como", "Eddie Vedder", "Dave Grohl", "Michael Stipe"],
    answer: "Eddie Vedder",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/CxKWTzr-k6s?t=21",
  },

  {
    question:
      "He was a huge part of this band's unique sound. Who was the drummer for The Police?",
    options: ["Dave Grohl", "Stewart Copeland", "John Bonham", "Neil Pert"],
    answer: "Stewart Copeland",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/zPwMdZOlPo8?list=RDzPwMdZOlPo8&t=6",
  },

  {
    question:
      "'Reasons' and 'Shining Star' were huge hits for this band in the mid 1970's?",
    options: [
      "Parliament",
      "Kool and the Gang",
      "Earth, Wind and Fire",
      "The O'Jays",
    ],
    answer: "Earth, Wind and Fire",
    audioSrc: "https://youtu.be/0Qz_b1di3i8?t=3",
  },

  // Add more questions here
];
// !variable to keep track of current question and score
let currentQuestionIndex = 0;
let score = 0;
// !variable stores reference to html
const questionElement = document.getElementById("question");
const optionsElement = document.getElementById("options");
const scoreElement = document.getElementById("score");
// eliminated the old code to get rid of buttons that were no longer being used

// const playButton = document.getElementById('play-song');
// const audio = document.getElementById('audio');
const audioSource = document.getElementById("audio-source");

function displayQuestion() {
  const currentQuestion = questions[currentQuestionIndex];
  const questionText = currentQuestion.question;
  // !adjust line break for css purposes
  const lineBreakThreshold = 10;
  // adjust for shorter questions as it affects the css//

  if (questionText.length > lineBreakThreshold) {
    questionElement.textContent = questionText;
  } else {
    questionElement.innerHTML = questionText.replace(/\n/g, "<br>");
  }
  // ! event listener to click on answer/option
  optionsElement.innerHTML = "";
  currentQuestion.options.forEach((option) => {
    const li = document.createElement("li");
    li.textContent = option;
    li.addEventListener("click", () => checkAnswer(option));
    optionsElement.appendChild(li);
  });
}
// !Previous code prior to replacing it with swal.fire
// function checkAnswer(selectedOption) {
//   const currentQuestion = questions[currentQuestionIndex];
//   if (selectedOption === currentQuestion.answer) {
//     score++;
//     scoreElement.textContent = score;
//     playAudio(audioSource);
//   }
//   currentQuestionIndex++;
//   if (currentQuestionIndex < questions.length) {
//     displayQuestion();
//   } else {
//     alert('Game Over! Your final score is ' + score);
//   }
// }
// !this section add 1 point to score
function checkAnswer(selectedOption) {
  const currentQuestion = questions[currentQuestionIndex];
  if (selectedOption === currentQuestion.answer) {
    score++;
    scoreElement.textContent = score;
    Swal.fire({
      title: "Nice job!",
      html:
        '<a href="' +
        currentQuestion.audioSrc +
        '" target="_blank">Click here to play the song</a>',
      icon: "success",
      confirmButtonText: "Next Question",
    }).then((result) => {
      if (result.isConfirmed) {
        playAudio(currentQuestion.audioSrc);
        currentQuestionIndex++;
        if (currentQuestionIndex < questions.length) {
          displayQuestion();
        } else {
          Swal.fire("Game Over!", "Your final score is " + score, "info");
        }
      }
    });
  } else {
    currentQuestionIndex++;
    if (currentQuestionIndex < questions.length) {
      displayQuestion();
    } else {
      Swal.fire("Game Over!", "Your final score is " + score, "info");
    }
  }
}

// !This section allows for audio source
function playAudio(audioSrc) {
  audioSource.src = audioSrc;
  audio.load();
  audio.play();
}

document.getElementById("next-button").addEventListener("click", () => {
  if (currentQuestionIndex < questions.length) {
    displayQuestion();
  }
});

document.getElementById("start-over").addEventListener("click", () => {
  startOver();
});
// !start over section reverts to 0
function startOver() {
  currentQuestionIndex = 0;
  score = 0;
  scoreElement.textContent = score;
  displayQuestion();
}
displayQuestion();


// Add a pop up for the "how to play"!
const divPopUp = document.getElementById('how-to-play-popup')
const xButton = document.getElementById('x-button-popup')
document.getElementById('how-to-play').addEventListener('click', () => {
  console.log('button is press it')
  divPopUp.style.display = 'block';
  xButton.style.display = 'block';
})

document.getElementById('x-button-popup').addEventListener('click', () => {
  divPopUp.style.display = 'none';
  xButton.style.display = 'none';
})